Travis Hanneman

thanneman1@gmail.com Scottsdale, AZ

Full-stack Developer

github.com/thanneman linkedin.com/in/thanneman thanneman.com

Summary

I'm a Full Stack Developer with experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Git, RESTful APIs, data structure, and computer algorithms. I'm a strong media and communication professional with a Bachelor's Degree focused in Design Studies from Arizona State University.

Recent Projects

WatchThisWhere | GitHub | Live

- Find where to stream your favorite movies and tv shows with WatchThisWhere.
- Tech: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js

One-Liner | GitHub | Live

- A comical community to post and rate the best jokes.
- Tech: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Mocha, Chai

Discscore | GitHub | Live

- Quickly track your disc golf games, scores, and locations.
- Tech: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Mocha, Chai

Experience

Progressive Insurance Remote/Gilbert, AZ Frontend Developer II July 2020 – Current

- Investigate and identify user needs through web analytic data, competitor and web industry research, and user research techniques.
- Develop project requirements with detailed scope including wireframes, process flow diagrams, mock-ups, and prototypes.
- Analyze suitability, business benefit, and cost-effectiveness of efforts.

Deluxe Corporation Remote

Web Services Specialist/Developer

Oct 2018 - July 2020

- Build/manage storefronts for clients. Including: add/remove products, update HTML/CSS branding, building/update templates for customizable products.
- Provide support, management, and development of company web technology & application services.
- Collaborate with the development team on any bugs, client requests, and product builds.

Chive Media Group Austin, TX Nov 2014 - Oct 2018

Manager, Editorial Operations

- Managed a team of 13 employees of the editorial team for the CHIVE.com.
- Reported insights and Key Performance Indicators to the C-level executives for editorial and social media departments.
- Integrated with both the Sales and Product departments to effectively implement new ideas, solutions, and procedures to promote growth.

Education

Thinkful Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

Computer Software Engineering

Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Mocha, Chai, Git, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.

Arizona State University